hello today's video will be about cash
poisoning
first we'll take a look how it was
possible to redirect
all our abuse reports on github to
completely innocent victim
and later we'll see how firefox updates
could be completely disabled
the whole video is based on an excellent
research
done by james cattle links to his white
paper
and his talk are in the description
enjoy
let's start by explaining why do we even
use cache
when a user opens a website the request
travels like this
through the reverse proxy to the
application server
sometimes the application server has to
process the request
before sending the response however
many times the request is very simple
and can be the same
for all users for example index.html
in such case the same response can be
returned
every single time without consuming a
precious time
of application server that's exactly
what shared cache does and make sure to
not confuse it
with the local cache that is stored
inside your browser
sometimes the server tells us if the
response comes from cache
or not by using hit or miss in headers
if not we can determine it based on the
time
because the response from the cache will
be much quicker
but how does it actually cache it
the application server sends headers
that
tell the cache server whether he can
store a specific response
or not for example a request
to a resource that only we have access
to must never be cached
but when headers allow it the cache
server
saves the response before sending it to
this
particular user and then it stores it
for a specified
amount of time then for each request
it has to decide whether he can use a
cached response
or he has to forward the request to the
application server
that's when a cache key is being used
it's a signature of a request based on
which
the cache server decides what to do
a simple cache key could look like this
and if all those parameters match then
the cache server
decides that it can respond with a saved
response
the inputs that are included in the
cache key
are called kit inputs and all the other
ones
are unkit inputs and the idea
behind web cache poisoning attacks is to
find
an unkit input that will be ignored by
the cache server
but will be considered by the
application server
for example many php applications
support x original url header
so both requests on the screen will be
treated the same way
by the php server but they will have
completely different
cache key in such case we can
poison the cache using such a request
so when a legitimate user tries to visit
index.html he will get a response from
cache
from the path specified by us
but where is the impact you may ask
the easy way of exploiting such issues
is to increase the impact
of reflected cross-site scripting or
unexploitable
exercises but more often than not
you will not have an xss and in such
case you need to get creative let's see
how james got creative on github's
website
this is a standard get request
parameters
are where they always are which is in
the url
and how about this request it seems
valid but do you think that web
application servers
will actually use those parameters
turns out that some frameworks do and
one of them
is ruby on rails which was used to
develop
github website if you send such requests
then github will prioritize the
parameters
from the body but varnish cache server
will use the parameter from the url in
its cache key
this way you can poison any
parameterized request
with arbitrary values what could you do
with it
on github for example there is a report
abuse
functionality and you could poison the
url
that would be used to report your
account
and redirect the abuse report to
completely
innocent victim you could also
manipulate filters
deny access to topics or disable
the row button on files github
paid for this report 10 thousand dollars
many times you can use cash poisoning to
cause
denial of service this is often
not very impactful and not very welcome
by triagers
however in my next example you could
disable
updates for firefox browser which would
be critical
in case if there would be a fix for
zero-day vulnerability
keeping all the users insecure
uri normalization is a process that is
supposed to catch
and normalize all the uris that are
written slightly differently
but at the end meet the same address
for example the process of normalization
might include
url decoding the address and firefox
servers
use nginx for caching and the problem
was
that in such case nginx would forward
the request
to the application server without any
normalization
while the cache key is being url decoded
it means that both of these requests
would have
the same cache key but only the first
one
is valid it's send every time you start
up your firefox browser
to check if there are any updates
available
while the second one without url
decoding
will be considered completely invalid
path
in such case the server instead of
returning a 404 not found
it will redirect the user to main
mozilla page
and if you poison the cache this way all
the requests
that are meant to check for updates will
not actually
check for updates at all and firefox
paid 5 thousand dollars for this
vulnerability
and that's it for today's video if you
like the cash poisoning attacks
go see james stock on this topic the
link is in the card
as well as in the description down below
and if you like my explanations
go watch other videos on my channel but
for now
thanks for watching and goodbye